你喜欢那样吗?
Do you like that?
噢, 哈里.
Oh, Harry.
乔西.
Josie.
是的.
Yes.
是, 是我.
Yes, it's me.
我在这儿呢.
l'm here.
- 乔西.
- 哈里, 我在这儿.
- Josie.
- Harry, l'm here.
乔西...
Josie...
客房服务.
Room service.
进来吧, 门没锁.
Come on in, it's open.
你把它放在桌子上就行了.
You can just put it on the table.
欧蕊.
Audrey.
我相信你睡的还不错吧?
l trust your sleep was untroubled?
在大北方这儿,
我们的目标是让你住的
Here at The Great Northern,
we aim to make your stay
尽可能舒适
和愉快.
as comfortable
and as enjoyable as possible.
你知道, 我们对客房服务
的概念非常重视.
You know, we take the concept
of room service very seriously.
你记得
你爷爷?
Do you remember
your grandfather?
一个出色的人,
我见过最聪明的人.
Colorful man,
one of the wisest l ever met.
你知道他曾经说过?
You know what he once said?
他说如果你打算带上一个锤子
的话, 最好也把钉子一起带上.
He said if you're gonna bring
a hammer, you better bring nails.
那是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
那就是说下次
你进来我房间时
What that means is the next time
you come into my room
要继续进行下去,
你最好随时准备完成
and carry on,
you'd better be ready to finish
你进来这儿
最开始想要做的事.
whatever it is
you came here to start.
- 也许我现在已经准备好了.
- 然后做自己就好了.
- Maybe l'm ready now.
- Then be yourself.
我一直都在做我自己.
l am being myself.
你是对的.
You're right.
你绝对正确.
You're absolutely right.
我认错, 你是一个美丽,
有才智的年轻女子.
l stand corrected, you're a beautiful,
intelligent young woman.
还有呢?
What else?
你带有一种令人
不可抗拒的魔力...
You have an undeniable
magic about you...
...让我灵机一动.
...that inspires a plan.
在日暮中飞行之后2人晚餐如何?
Flight at sunset and dinner for two?
- 几时?
- 什么几时, 在日暮中飞行?
- When?
- What, the flight or the sunset?
不过,我还要去图书馆
晚些还要和我爸见面.
Well, l have to go to the library and
have a meeting with my father later.
就简单一句：去还是不去.
A simple yes or no would do.
去.
Yes.
那如果你要带锤子去的话,
最好也带上钉子哦.
And if you bring a hammer,
you better bring some nails too.
怎样了?
Anything?
不, 一句话也不说. 她要和
南非领事馆谈.
No, not a word. She wants to speak
to the South African consulate.
在双峰镇?
ln Twin Peaks?
为什么埃卡想我死?
Why would Eckhardt want me dead?
性嫉妒.
Sexual jealousy.
哦, 是啊.
Oh, yeah.
你回来了真好, 哈里.
lt's good to have you back, Harry.
晕船似的天旋地转
花了我一天才回过神来.
Taken me a day
or so to get my sea legs.
嗯, 老实说, 你看起来
还真像刚下船的样子.
Well, to be honest, it looks like
you went down with the ship.
你为什么不回家
好好休养一下?
Why don't you go home
and recuperate?
不, 我只想喝点咖啡,
或者再来点吃的.
No, all l need is some coffee,
maybe a little food.
这肯定是治愈宿醉的良方, 哈里.
Sure-fire cure for a hangover, Harry.
你拿一杯几乎结冰的,
未经过滤的番茄汁.
You take a glass of nearly frozen,
unstrained tomato juice.
你扑通一声,把一对生蚝搭进去
一口气喝光.
You plop a couple of oysters in there,
you drink it down.
深呼吸.
Breathe deeply.
之后, 你再来一份劲量级的,
我是说一份劲量级的牛羊杂碎,
Next, you take a mound,
and l mean a mound, of sweetbreads,
伴点栗子
和加拿大培根肉.
saute them with some chestnuts
and some Canadian bacon.
最后, 再来个圆面包.
Finally, biscuits.
大的, 整个闷浸到肉汁里.
Big biscuits, smothered in gravy.
好了现在, 这种吃法有个小秘诀,
你一定加些凤尾鱼--
Now, here's where it gets tricky,
you're gonna need some anchovies--
不行了.
Excuse me.
就该那样做的.
That should do it.
盆栽. 终极缩影.
The bonsai. The ultimate miniature.
小苏打水,
终极助消化.
Bicarbonate of soda,
the ultimate digestive aid.
哈里, 一口气喝光就会好了.
Harry, quaff in good health.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
那个东东到底从什么鬼地方来的?
Where the hell did that come from?
这是今天上午送来的.
lt was delivered this morning.
乔西送的.
lt's from Josie.
哈里, 云顿·厄尔
来过我家了.
Harry, Windom Earle
was at my house.
云顿·厄尔. 什么时候?
Windom Earle. When?
昨天. 他把这个留给了唐娜.
Yesterday. He left this with Donna.
他正接近, 哈里.
He's closing in, Harry.
骑士对国王三主教.
我们要该做什么?
Knight to king bishop 3.
What do we do?
我们今天要发布我们的下一步行动.
We publish our next move today.
谢谢, 露西.
Thanks, Lucy.
你自己可撑住了, 哈里.
Brace yourself, Harry.
- 戴尔·库珀探员.
- 戈登·寇尔.
- Agent Dale Cooper.
- Gordon Cole.
不好意思打断你们了，伙计们.
Sure sorry to interrupt you fellas.
但是, 库, 我给你带了
云顿·厄尔的
But, Coop, l'm bringing you
the classified portion
部分分类档案.
of the Windom Earle dossier.
Back from Bend?
刚从本德，俄勒冈州回来.
Been on over to Bend, Oregon.
整个本德
到处都乱套了.
Whole lot of shaking
going on down in Bend.
戈登·寇尔也加入了.
Enter Gordon Cole.
这真叫人心烦, 里欧.
This is so galling, Leo.
小戴尔正在不断拒绝
公平游戏!
Young Dale is continually refusing
to play fair!
当时厄尔晕过去:
When Earle went:
医生发现
他使用了强力安定药氟?啶醇.
the doctors discovered
he was on haloperidol.
和独臂人杰勒德
以前用的药一样.
The same drug the one-armed man,
Gerard, was on.
- 什么?
- 杰勒德用同样的药.
- What's that?
- Gerard used the same drug.
你对了.
You got it.
但他们推测他是用
这种药来装病
But they figured he was using
the drug to fake his illness
正如你所怀疑的, 库.
just as you suspected, Coop.
明显是精神分裂病患的伎俩.
Definite schizoid maneuvering.
"蓝皮书计划?"
''Project Blue Book?''
我的天啊, 戈登,
他和这有什么关系?
My God, Gordon,
what was he doing on this?
1965年，局里把厄尔
借给空军部.
The Bureau loaned Earle out
to the Air Force in 1 965.
他那2年期间的报告
都被涂黑删除了. 为了国家安全.
Reports on his two-year hitch
are blacked out. National security.
等一下.
Wait a minute.
厄尔当时也在调查UFOs?
Earle was investigating UFOs?
布里格斯少校, 哈里.
Major Briggs, Harry.
戈登, 这里面的连接
有古怪.
Gordon, there are some
curious linkages here.
连接这个词
让我联想到了香肠.
The word linkage
reminds me of sausage.
别想太多什么连接了,
不如想想小肉饼吧.
Never cared much for the links,
preferred the patties.
但早餐才是一个真正的好主意.
But breakfast is a real good idea.
盆栽.
Bonsai.
还记得那些
二战时期的老电影吗?
Remember those
old World War ll movies?
盆栽!
Bonsai!
混帐东西!
Damnation!
再次见到你真好, 医生.
警长, 我们等一下和你们一起坐车.
Good to see you again, doc.
Sheriff, we'll be riding with you.
巡警车就在外面等着.
Cruiser's right outside.
你留下来一会儿, 库.
Hold it one second there, Coop.
你赶快把自己那套
尘封的黑西装解封吧.
You'd better dust off
your own black suit.
有云顿·厄尔
在此兴风作浪,
With Windom Earle
rolling around loose on the deck,
我们需要你重新归队.
we need you back on the team.
你在说什么啊, 戈登?
What are you saying, Gordon?
库, 我真高兴极了
我正式通知
Coop, it gives me great pleasure
to reinstate you
你复职
回到联邦调查局.
into the Federal Bureau
of lnvestigation.
全新发放的,
更精准和高效.
Brand-new issue,
more accurate and efficient.
史密夫威信, 10毫米.
Smith & Wesson, ten millimeter.
1076型号, 全不锈钢.
Model 1 076, all stainless steel.
真是一把漂亮的武器, 库,
现在它都是你的了.
lt's a beautiful weapon, Coop,
and it's all yours.
谢谢你, 戈登.
Thank you, Gordon.
库珀, 我们一定要找到厄尔.
我们会追捕,
Cooper, we're gonna find Earle.
We will pursue,
- 捉拿和监禁.
- capture and incarcerate.
- Capture and incarcerate.
那我们上路吧.
Let's hit the road.
快跟上, 小鬼, 我请客.
Come on, buster, l'm buying.
紧随你尾后, 戈登.
On your tail, Gordon.
现在, 里欧...
Now, Leo...
...选3张牌.
...pick three cards.
一,
One,
二,
two,
三.
three.
唐娜皇后.
Queen Donna.
欧蕊皇后.
Queen Audrey.
雪莉皇后, 好.
Queen Shelly, good.
现在, 看你能否找到国王.
Now, see if you can find the king.
小戴尔.
Little Dale.
现在, 我们还需要多一个皇后.
Now, we need one more queen.
我们来瞧瞧看.
Let's see.
红心皇后.
The queen of hearts.
让我看看.
Let me see.
双峰小姐.
Miss Twin Peaks.
那么, 如果你赢了你会得到什么?
你会得到一打玫瑰,
Now, what do you get if you win?
You get a dozen roses,
得到你报读那所大学的
奖学金,
a scholarship to the college
of your choice,
得到你同辈们的赞美...
the accolades of your peers...
噢, 是, 我知道了.
Oh, yes, l know.
你还会得到死亡.
You get to die.
一个皇室般的处决仪式.
A royal execution.
而库珀...
And Cooper...
...只能眼睁睁在那儿看着他们死去.
...gets to watch.
你好, 本.
Hello, Ben.
我要和你谈谈.
l need to talk to you.
感觉如何, 先生?
How was everything, sir?
简直好的超乎想像.
Unbelievable.
- 欧蕊·荷恩在吗?
- 她在后台. 我帮你去找她.
- ls Audrey Horne here?
- She's in the back. l'll get her for you.
谢谢.
Thanks.
唐娜, 嗨.
Donna, hi.
嗨, 唐娜.
Hi, Donna.
嗨.
Hi.
- 嗨, 唐娜.
- 嗨.
- Hi, Donna.
- Hi.
- 我能和你讲几分钟吗?
- 当然可以.
- Can l talk to you for a minute?
- Sure.
这听起来可能有点儿奇怪.
This might sound a little strange.
怎么啦?
What?
你知道有什么原因
我妈会来探访你爸呢?
Would you know any reason
why my mom's visiting your dad?
毫无头绪.
Not offhand.
恩, 是这样的, 昨天,
他来我家见我妈.
Okay, well, yesterday,
he came by the house to see my mom.
然后今天,
她就来这儿回访他了.
And today,
she drove over here to see him.
或许她只是来帮他
进行停止格斯伍计划而已.
Maybe she's just helping him
with the Stop Ghostwood campaign.
不, 如果是的话，她会和我说的
但她一个字也没提.
No, she would have said something
to me, and she hasn't said a word.
她现在还在这儿吗?
ls she here now?
一起在办公室里.
They're in his office together.
不, 我不会接受它们的.
No, l won't accept them.
它们是你的信.
They're your letters.
它们是写给你的.
They were written to you.
我不想要它们了.
l don't want them.
我不会再把它们
留在我家里了.
l won't have them
in my house any longer.
你都已经留着它们20年了.
You've had them for 20 years.
为什么现在才这样做?
Why now?
那正是我想问你的.
为什么现在才这样做?
That's just what l'm asking you.
Why now?
它们只会把
旧伤疤挖开.
They'll only succeed
in ripping apart old wounds.
一想到这儿我就受不了.
l can't bear the thought of it.
艾琳.
Eileen.
艾琳, 为什么你不相信我呢?
Eileen, why don't you believe me?
口头说的不足以信.
Words aren't good enough.
我要以行动来向你说明一切.
难道你还没有听到吗?
l want my actions to speak for me.
Haven't you been listening?
这些年来我一直都是错的.
l have been wrong all these years.
现在我尝试着去弥补它.
l am trying to make up for it.
但往往是
做多错多.
Sometimes, making up for things
only makes it worse.
噢, 艾琳.
Oh, Eileen.
你本该是我一生人中
拥有过最美好的事.
You should have been the best thing
that ever happened to me.
本, 别这样.
Ben, please.
自从那晚之后我就再也没抱过你了.
l haven't held you since that night.
别.
Don't.
噢, 我好想抱着你.
Oh, l wanna hold you.
我好想回到过去.
l wanna go back.
- 上帝, 如果你只是--
- 求你了, 别这样!
- God, if you'd just--
- Please, don't!
对不起.
l'm sorry.
- 你告诉她过吗?
- 上帝啊, 没有.
- Have you told her?
- God, no.
从没有. 以后也不会.
你必须答应我你也要做到.
Never. l never will.
And you must promise me the same.
你绝对不可以再来找我了.
You mustn't come over again.
你必须离她远点.
You must stay away from her.
我明白.
l understand.
希望你真的明白.
l hope you do.
这到底是在搞什么鬼啊?
What the hell was that all about?
我不知道.
l don't know.
但我一定要找出真相.
But l'm gonna find out.
哈里, 有一个最好的解酒方法
我每次碰到宿醉都管用
Harry, the best cure l ever came
across for a hangover
就是生肉, 吃很多很多生肉.
was raw meat, and plenty of it.
你打一个生蛋在上面.
You break an egg on it.
再加点腌渍凤尾鱼,
土八哥辣椒仔和伍斯特郡劲辣油.
Add in some salted anchovies,
Tabasco and Worcestershire sauce.
如果你想吃,
我们可以帮你点一份.
lf you want,
we can order up some for you.
现在到我说了, 库,
你知我现在想吃什么吗?
Now that l come to mention it, Coop,
you know what l'm in the mood for?
想吃什么, 戈登?
What's that, Gordon?
一份5成熟的牛排,
你可以在蒂芬妮珠宝店出售了.
A steak so rare,
you could sell it at Tiffany's.
那, 你可来对地方了.
Well, you've come to the right place.
太好了.
Good deal.
圣灵啊, 那是谁啊?
Holy smokes, who is that?
雪莉·强生.
Shelly Johnson.
真是个美人儿.
What a beauty.
让我想起那个雕塑,
那个没手臂的小美人儿.
Kind of reminds me of that statue,
the babe without the arms.
- 维纳斯·迪·麦咯.
- 名字叫麦咯,
- Venus de Milo.
- The name was Milo,
但那个是题外话了.
but that's beside the point.
那个女孩让你
产生想讲点法语的愿望.
That's the kind of girl to make you wish
you spoke a little French.
失陪一下, 库, 我要去小柜台
那边试试讲世界语了.
Excuse me, Coop, while l try my hand
at a little counter Esperanto.
祝你好运, 戈登.
Good luck, Gordon.
你好.
Hello.
我正在想能否麻烦你
给我来一杯浓的原味黑咖啡.
l was wondering if l might trouble you
for a cup of strong, black coffee.
然后在你煮咖啡的过程里,
And in the process,
我答应你，会给你讲些非常
好玩有趣的奇闻轶事.
engage you with an anecdote
of no small amusement.
我名字是戈登·寇尔,
The name is Gordon Cole,
我在那卡座里
就已经忍不住要注视你的美丽了.
and l couldn't help
but notice you from the booth.
然后...哇, 现在近距离看着你的美,
And...well, seeing your beauty now,
我感觉彷彿装满了一胃大黄蜂
心慌意乱，五脏六腑翻江倒海.
l feel as though my stomach is filled
with a team of bumblebees.
你没必要说那么大声,
我能听见.
You don't have to shout,
l can hear you.
我听见了.
l heard that.
除了咖啡
你还要别的吗?
Do you want anything
besides coffee?
我能清楚听到你说话.
l heard you perfectly.
我能听见你说话, 真的, 拜托了--
And l can hear you, honest, please--
你不明白.
You don't understand.
你不明白, 强生小姐.
你看见这些了?
You don't understand, Miss Johnson.
Do you see these?
20年来, 我一直要求
别人一定要高声说话,
For 20 years, l've been
asking people to please speak up,
但这实在太奇怪了,
我竟能听见你声如洪钟.
but for some weird reason,
l can hear you clear as a bell.
在说点别的.
Say something else.
你要来个馅饼送咖啡吗?
Do you want pie with your coffee?
好家伙. 我能一清二楚的听见你说话.
Good Lord. l can hear you perfectly.
这可有点像奇迹降临了.
一个超凡现象.
This is like some kind of miracle.
A phenomenon.
- 这算哪门子奇迹?
- 什么?
- What's wrong with miracles?
- What's that?
这樱桃馅饼才是一个奇迹.
This cherry pie is a miracle.
能拜托你问这位拿圆木
的女士大声点说话吗?
Would you please ask the lady
with the log to speak up?
是馅饼, 她刚刚
樱桃馅饼的事.
The pie, she was talking
about the cherry pie.
我又听见你说话了. 我又听见你说话了.
l heard you again. l heard you again.
那你要来点馅饼吗?
Would you like some pie?
来个巨大的, 有大量馅的.
Massive, massive quantities.
喝一杯水, 甜心,
我浑身火烫啊.
And a glass of water, sweetheart,
my socks are on fire.
哈里.
Harry.
站在道奇跑车上的那只
好像是山雀.
That looks like a chickadee
on a Dodge Dart.
不像, 道奇跑车上的
倒像是一只百灵鸟.
No, it looks like a finch
on a Dodge Dart.
不是, 道奇跑车上的是山雀.
Nope, chickadee on a Dodge Dart.
- 嗨.
- 嗨. 来杯浓黑咖啡?
- Hi.
- Hi. Cup of deep black joe?
这还用说.
You bet.
对解酒
你有什么好方法介绍?
What do you recommend
for a hangover?
滴酒不沾和做祷告.
Teetotaling and prayer.
回答的好.
Good answer.
我来点咖啡吧.
l'll try some coffee.
你今天过得怎样?
How are you today?
我很好.
l'm fine.
其实, 是怪异才对.
l'm weird, actually.
我迷失方向了，都找不着北,
l'm disoriented,
我都不知道我现在在哪儿.
我意思是, 我知道我在哪儿,
l'm not sure where l am.
l mean, l know where l am,
但在这儿呆着让人感觉很古怪.
but it feels odd being here.
我没事.
l'm okay.
会好的.
Okay.
听我说, 我一直在生活在
社会之外，好长一段时间了,
Listen to me, l've been out
of circulation so long,
那些社交礼节
我全都忘了.
l've completely forgotten
the social niceties.
比如, 你问我过得怎样阿,
l mean, you ask me how l am,
我不会真的准确回答你
我如何如何.
l'm not really supposed
to say how l am.
我想必会这样说,
"我很好, 谢谢. 你呢"
l'm supposed to say,
''l'm fine, thanks. How are you?''
我很好, 谢谢.
l'm fine, thanks.
- 你肯定觉得我很奇怪.
- 没有.
- You must think l'm really strange.
- No.
不过, 按照理应尊重的
社会客套礼节,
Well, with due respect
to the social niceties,
既使你真的觉得我很奇怪,
但你也不会对我说的, 对吧?
even if you did think l was strange,
you wouldn't tell me, would you?
没有的事, 如果我认为你是个怪人,
我会告诉你.
No, if l thought you were strange,
l'd tell you.
而你不觉得?
And you don't think so?
一点也不.
Not a bit.
好. 很高兴我们搞清楚了.
Good. Glad we got that cleared up.
那, 你要点什么呢?
So, what will you have?
我要一个鸡肉夹馍
和一份大杯装牛奶, 谢谢.
l would like a chicken potpie
and a large glass of milk, please.
你很会点.
所有主食都很具代表性.
Good choice.
All the major food groups represented.
我要火鸡三明治, 全麦的,
生菜, 加一勺蛋黄酱,
Turkey sandwich, whole wheat,
lettuce, dollop of mayonnaise,
然后我给你讲个笑话.
and l've got a joke for you.
2只企鹅正走着
准备翻过冰川.
Two penguins were walking
across an iceberg.
一只企鹅转过身来
对第二只企鹅说:
One penguin turned
to the second penguin and said:
"你看起来像
穿这一件晚礼服."
''You look like
you're wearing a tuxedo.''
安妮?
Annie?
我听到那个啦.
l heard that.
稍等一下, 我马上就回来.
Wait a minute, l'll be right back.
我还没完全讲完呢.
l wasn't quite finished.
你爱上她
有多久了?
How long you been
in love with her?
哈里, 谁说着和爱
有关了?
Harry, who said anything
about love?
库, 你刚刚还试着给她讲笑话呢.
Coop, you just tried to tell her a joke.
我有吗?
l did?
好了, 那第二只企鹅
怎么说?
So, what did
the second penguin say?
哦, 第一只企鹅
对第二只企鹅说:
Well, the first penguin said
to the second penguin:
"你看起来像
穿这一件晚礼服."
''You look like
you're wearing a tuxedo.''
然后第二只企鹅说,
"我或许真的穿着晚礼服."
And the second penguin said,
''Maybe l am.''
终于自我圆场完毕了.
The defense rests.
你想再来点馅饼吗?
还是要整个馅饼?
Do you want some more pie?
A whole pie?
是的, 我会的, 强生小姐,
还要一张纸和笔.
Yes, l would, Miss Johnson,
and a piece of paper and a pencil.
我计划要为这个光芒四射的馅饼
写一首叙事诗.
l plan on writing an epic poem
about this gorgeous pie.
好的.
Okay.
我见你去过猫头鹰山洞.
l see that you've been to Owl Cave.
什么?
Sorry?
嗯, 那个图案看起来就像一个
面朝上的猫头鹰山洞.
Well, that design looks like
the one up at Owl Cave.
让我看看那个.
Let me see that.
我把布里格斯少校的纹身
和圆木姑姑的加在一起.
l combined Major Briggs' tattoo
with the Log Lady's.
这看起来的确
像一个猫头鹰山洞.
This looks exactly
like the one at Owl Cave.
哈里, 我得去看看这个猫头鹰山洞.
Harry, l've got to see this Owl Cave.
亲爱的唐娜,
Dear Donna,
你是对的, 我必须离开.
You were right, l had to go.
但你上路了
一切事就会不同了.
Everything feels different
when you're on the road.
这感觉好多了.
lt feels better.
旧金山真的很酷.
San Francisco's really cool.
下一站, 墨西哥.
Next stop, Mexico.
我会带着无数故事回来的.
l'll be back with a million stories.
我保证.
l promise.
我爱你, 詹姆斯.
l love you, James.
詹姆斯?
James?
他好吗?
How is he?
他很好.
He's good.
他正做其所需.
He's doing what he needed to do.
他会回来的.
He'll be back.
爸, 我能问你些事吗?
Dad, can l ask you something?
当然了.
Sure.
妈怎么会认识
本杰明·荷恩?
How does Mom know
Benjamin Horne?
我想她不认识吧, 唐娜.
不大清楚.
l doubt that she does, Donna.
Not very well.
他昨天来过这儿.
He was over here yesterday.
他们就像老朋友叙旧似的.
They were talking like old friends.
你妈妈和很多本地的
慈善团体有工作关系.
Your mother works a lot
with the local charities.
我肯定就连本也会
捐助一次吧.
l'm sure even Ben contributes
once in a while.
她今早又开车去大北方
见他去了.
She drove to The Great Northern
this morning to see him again.
可能是谈
募捐基金的事吧.
Probably something to do
with a fundraiser.
我不这么认为.
l don't think so.
是的, 确实是那样的,
早餐时她和我说过了.
Yeah, that's exactly what it was,
she told me at breakfast.
是一个关于『治愈我们的星球』计划的事.
One of those heal-the-planet things.
那, 她没想我提过这事.
Well, she didn't mention it to me.
好了, 事实就是这样,
那时她告诉我的.
Well, that's exactly what it was,
that's what she told me.
我去开吧.
l'll get it.
嗨, 我是来给海沃德太太
送快递的.
Hi, l have a delivery
for Mrs. Hayward.
他们说这花是送给妈的.
They said they're for Mom.
没有贺卡.
No card.
我去把它们养在水里.
l'll put them in water.
对不起, 对不起, 是我不好.
Sorry, sorry, my fault.
- 我没听见你走过来.
- 没事.
- l didn't hear you.
- No.
没有谁规定
一个人的脑袋和一个人的脚
One should never allow
one's mind and one's foot
要同步的.
to wander at the same time.
艾活·柏金斯.
我再次向你道歉.
Edward Perkins.
Once again, my apologies.
欧蕊·荷恩.
认识你真好, 柏金斯先生.
Audrey Horne.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Perkins.
那, 你在图书馆干嘛?
So, what brings you to the library?
我正在研究
和平演变.
l'm doing research
on civil disobedience.
你研究这个好. 现在就靠
你们这些年轻人去抵抗了.
Good for you. lt is incumbent
on the young to disobey.
你是个教授吗?
Are you a professor?
嗯, 在我的领域里,
教诗歌是我的专长.
Well, l teach,
poetry is my area of expertise.
你在开玩笑吧? 你知道吗, 有人
给我寄了一首诗, 或许你读的懂.
You're kidding. You know, someone
sent me a poem, maybe you know it.
哦, 我可能会.
现在, 我们来看看.
Oh, perhaps l do.
Now, let's have a look.
你来读.
You read it.
好.
Okay.
看那山峰高耸入云,
犹如波涛延绵不断
See the mountains kiss high heaven,
And the waves clasp one another,
没有一朵姐妹花会被宽恕
如果它鄙视它的兄弟
No sister-flower would be forgiven
lf it disdain'd its brother,
阳光紧扣着大地,
月光则亲吻着大海
And the sunlight clasps the earth,
And the moonbeams kiss the sea
如果汝不吻我,
这世间一切的甜蜜之事价值何在呢?
What is all this sweet work worth,
lf thou kiss not me?
对, 你知道这首诗.
Yeah, you know it.
知道. 是英国诗人雪莱的诗.
Yes. Shelley.
什么?
What?
凝视着你
Gazing at you
朗诵雪莱的诗,
reciting the verse of Shelley,
你看起来真的非常像一位皇后.
you look very much like a queen.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
我想我要先走了.
很高兴能遇见你.
l guess l better be going.
Nice meeting you.
- 或许某日我们会再相遇的.
- 对.
- Perhaps we'll meet again someday.
- Yeah.
- 想参加吗?
- 不.
- Thinking of entering?
- No.
我觉得就算没有这些
穿这泳装和高跟鞋
l think the real world's strange enough
without getting on-stage
在舞台上巡游的表演
这个现实世界本身就已经够怪异了.
and parading around
in a bathing suit and heels.
我猜修道院要是搞这样的东西
地方肯定不够大.
Guess the convent's not too big
on that kind of stuff.
猜的对.
That's a good guess.
那, 回到文明世界的
感觉如何?
So, what's it like being back
in civilization?
和我呆在修道院阁楼
的确不一样.
lt's not like they kept us
up in an attic.
我是说, 其实我们也读报纸,
我们甚至还有有线电视.
l mean, we had newspapers,
we even had cable TV.
但每次我告诉别人我从哪来时，
他们都表现的好像我刚从牢里放出来一样.
Every time l tell someone where l've
been, they act like l'm out on parole.
对不起.
Sorry.
你知道我觉得最怪是什么?
又有男人在身边转悠了.
You know what is weird?
Being around men again.
那, 要是在修道院里的话
你就没必要花时间去适应那个了.
Well, you don't have to spend time
in a convent to feel that.
你了解
戴尔·库珀吗?
What do you know
about Dale Cooper?
我们感兴趣吗?
Are we interested?
谁这样说了?
Who said anything about that?
唔, 今天他看着你的时候
光看他脸的表情就能判断了,
Well, judging by the look on his face
when he saw you today,
我敢说你的机会最大.
l'd say you have a major opportunity.
不好意思, 你全搞错了.
Sorry, you have it all wrong.
我对此还远远不感兴趣呢.
l'm not even remotely interested.
安迪?
Andy?
是, 露西.
Yes, Lucy.
我想谢谢你昨天帮忙
平息了鼬鼠骚乱.
l wanna thank you for helping out
during the weasel riot yesterday.
我想对你说的话
比对那个基巴要说的多了.
Which is more than l can say
for a certain Dick we both know.
维持秩序是我的份内事.
Keeping the peace is part of my job.
你带着那齿轮
准备去哪儿啊?
Where are you going
with all of that gear?
去洞穴勘探.
Spelunking.
危险吗? 洞穴勘探?
ls it dangerous? Spelunking?
有时吧.
Sometimes.
答应我点事行不?
Promise me something?
好.
Okay.
我知道你会很坚强,
l know you'll be strong,
我也知道你会很勇敢,
and l know you'll be brave,
但我要你答应我
千万要小心.
but l want you to promise me
that you'll be careful.
我会小心的. 我向你保证.
l'll be careful. You have my word.
噢...亲爱的.
Oh...dear.
- 都搞好了, 哈里?
- 皮特刚刚走出了我们的下一步.
- All set, Harry?
- Pete just called in our next move.
- 我们的卒向他的主教暴露了.
- 要我打住吗?
- We expose a pawn to his bishop.
- Want me to hold off?
不, 皮特知道他在做什么.
No, Pete knows what he's doing.
如果他吃了那只卒,
他就会损失主教.
lf he takes that pawn,
he forfeits the bishop.
那么, 他就会前功尽弃了.
Thus, losing his initial advantage.
你感觉如何?
How you feeling?
就像有人用一个铁道钉
在我耳朵里猛捶猛穿一样.
Like someone pounded
a railroad spike through my ear.
那我们到秘密洞穴里,
去凉快凉快吧
Then a descent into a cool,
subterranean cave
就像医生吩咐的那样.
will be just what the doctor ordered.
寇尔能
爬上去吗?
Are you sure Cole's up
for the climb?
戈登不和我们去.
Gordon's not coming with us.
雪莉带他到海沃德医生那
看他的听力去了.
Shelly took him up to Doc Hayward's
to see about his hearing problem.
老掉牙的音叉测试.
The old tuning-fork test.
欧蕊?
Audrey?
杰克·肯尼迪
入主白宫时,
When Jack Kennedy
entered the White House,
他把他弟弟也接进去了.
he took his brother with him.
因为他相信波比
会和他讲真话的,
Because he trusted Bobby
to tell him the truth,
即使是在不太顺境时.
even when it wasn't pretty.
当猪湾被炸毁时
波比在那儿.
When the Bay of Pigs went up
in smoke, Bobby was there.
当俄国人把导弹扔进
菲德尔·卡斯特罗的后院时,
When the Russians moved
their missiles into Fidel's backyard,
波比在那儿帮助他的兄弟
并肩作战.
Bobby was there to help his brother
shoulder through.
你是指
杰里吗?
Sort of how Jerry's done that
for you?
我寻找的正是
这种毫无保留的真实.
lt's the unvarnished truth
that l am looking for.
而我相信你...
And l believe that you...
...就是最佳人选.
...are the best man for the job.
我?
Me?
欧蕊,
Audrey,
我知道我一直都
是个不称职的爸爸.
l know that l haven't been
a very good father.
噢, 真见鬼, 我这是在骗谁啊?
Oh, heck, who am l kidding?
我除了是一个低级庸俗的，贪婪的小人之外
何时何事我有称职过的?
When have l ever been anything
but a sleazy, rapacious heel?
嗯, 爸爸,
或许你在我小的时候称职过, 但--
Well, Daddy,
maybe when l was little, but--
的确是. 但我已经改过自新了.
Exactly. But l've changed.
而且我下定决心
要做一个好人.
And l am determined
to be a better person.
要成为那种
你终有一日会尊重的父亲.
The kind of father
that you will respect someday.
当我想到劳拉,
When l think about Laura,
当我想到我犯过的
那些错误,
when l think about the mistakes
that l've made,
我就想到要为我们全家人
构建一个幸福快乐的生活.
l want to build a life in happiness
for our whole family.
你, 我.
You, me.
你愿意帮助我去做吗?
Will you help me do that?
拜托了?
Please?
爸爸, 我是你的人.
Daddy, l'm your man.
太让我感动了.
Sensational.
欧蕊, 打点行装,
赶去机场,
Audrey, pack a bag,
get out to the airport,
你的航班一小时内起飞.
your plane leaves in an hour.
我的航班?
My plane?
噢, 庄. 你来得刚好
我正想找你呢.
Oh, John. Just the man
that l wanna see.
嗨, 本. 你好, 欧蕊.
Hi, Ben. Hello, Audrey.
- 爸爸--
- 欧蕊, 你最好快动身吧.
- Daddy--
- Audrey, you better get a move on.
1小时. 欧蕊今晚
赶去西雅图.
One hour. Audrey's on her way
to Seattle tonight.
她会和环保主义者们
一起参加早餐会议.
She's having a breakfast confab
with the environmentalists.
我们要把松鼬的事
这个...推向全国.
We're going national
with this...pine-weasel thing.
好极了, 那太好了.
Great, that's great.
爸爸, 这么突如其来
我不肯定我能马上走.
Daddy, l'm not sure l can leave
on such short notice.
好了, 这里是详情.
时间, 地点, 等等.
Now, here are the particulars.
Time, place, so on.
欧蕊, 你要给我们带
好消息回来.
Audrey, you bring us back
good news.
好消息.
Good news.
那好, 我想我要走了.
Well, guess l better go.
- 再见.
- Bye.
路上小心,  欧蕊.
Travel safely, Audrey.
庄.
John.
你怎样, 本?
How are you, Ben?
我感觉浑身都被
灌满了仁慈和善良.
l am filled to the brim
with a feeling of goodness.
就像一颗圣诞树
内心快活极了.
Like a Christmas tree
all lit up inside.
但每当夜里
我看着镜子,
But at the end of the day
when l look in the mirror,
我不得不面对一个事实
就是我真的不知道怎么才算是好.
l have to face the fact
that l really don't know how to be good.
你正向着公平公正出发，相当好.
You're off to a pretty fair start.
你是怎么做到的, 庄?
有什么秘密吗?
How do you do it, John?
What's the secret?
你真的认为
我可以学着做一个好人吗?
Do you really think
that l could learn to be good?
我觉得没什么不可以啊.
只要用心体会.
l don't see why not.
Just keep your eye on your heart.
而且永远说真话.
And always tell the truth.
- 永远说真话.
- 不过首先把最艰辛的真话讲出来.
- Always tell the truth.
- Tell the hardest truth first though.
哦, 总是把最艰辛的真话先讲出来.
噢, 我喜欢那样.
Oh, always tell the hardest truth first.
Oh, l love that.
庄, 那真是好极了.
John, that's terrific.
这说真话的事, 无疑是
善良的最前线.
This truth business, it's clearly
at the forefront of goodness.
本?
Ben?
- 我和你女儿相爱了.
- 对, 这个真话够硬.
- l'm falling in love with your daughter.
- Yeah, that's a hard truth.
- 好例子.
- 是真的.
- Good example.
- lt is the truth.
- 真的?
- 对.
- lt is?
- Yep.
噢, 庄.
Oh, John.
- 庄.
- 本.
- John.
- Ben.
我们身处的世界多美好啊.
What a wonderful world we live in.
- 小心点, 安迪.
- 抓紧了, 安迪.
- Come on, Andy.
- Get a good grip, Andy.
- 看到了.
- 就是那, 安迪.
- Do it.
- That's it, Andy.
- 看来很好.
- 手把手.
- Looking good.
- Hand over hand.
快到了. 放松点.
Almost there. Take it easy.
- 不, 别, 别. 别往下看. 别.
- 撑住了, 安迪. 别往下看.
- No, no, no. Don't look down. No.
- Hang on, Andy. Don't look down.
- 坚持住.
- 别往下看!
- Hang on.
- Don't look down!
- 安迪.
- 你还好吧?
- Andy.
- You okay?
我很好.
l'm fine.
真不敢相信.
lncredible.
我们小的时候
常常在这儿玩.
We used to play here
when l was a kid.
假装那是恶灵
在闹鬼.
Pretend that it was haunted
by fierce ghosts.
看来是酒鬼留下的.
Beer drinkers, by the look of it.
那个符号在哪儿?
Where's the symbol?
这边.
This way.
就在这.
lt's right here.
找到了.
There it is.
2个符号合并成
一个完整的大符号.
Two symbols combined
into a larger whole.
但那意味着什么呢?
But for what purpose?
我不知道.
l don't know.
这可问倒我了.
Beats me.
纹身代表问题.
The tattoos are the question.
那这个一定就是答案了.
This must be the answer.
卡住了.
lt's stuck.
我的镐子, 卡住了.
My pick, it's stuck.
噢, 我的天哪.
Oh, my God.
圣烟啊.
Holy smoke.
看那个.
Look at that.
我都干了什么啊?
What have l done?
伙计们, 我们的生活
大多是要靠巧合和运气.
Fellas, coincidence and fate
figure largely in our lives.
出现的是一个岩石雕塑
lt appears to be a petroglyph.
哈里, 我不知道
这将会把我们领向何方.
Harry, l have no idea
where this will lead us.
但我明显感觉到
它将是一个既惊奇又怪异的地方.
But l have a definite feeling it will be
a place both wonderful and strange.
晚上好.
我能帮你点什么, 小姐?
Good evening.
Can l help you, young lady?
是的, 我想来点喝的,
但我不确定想喝什么.
Yes, l would like something to drink,
but l'm not exactly sure what.
淑女们似乎都喜欢喝朗姆酒.
Ladies seem to like the rum.
朗姆酒. 就来杯朗姆酒吧
谢谢 .
Rum. l would like to have
a rum, please.
- 加...?
- 汤力水?
- With...?
- Tonic?
黛安, 星期四, 晚上9:05.
Diane, Thursday, 9:05 p.m.
我刚从一个叫猫头鹰山洞
的地方回来.
l've just returned from a place
called Owl Cave.
至于我是怎么去到那里
是一个相当复杂的故事.
How l got there
is a rather complicated story.
所有事情都起源于一对纹身...
lt all began with a pair of tattoos...
第一杯我请.
First one's on me.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
- 你好, 安妮.
- 嗨.
- Hello, Annie.
- Hi.
- 我给你买什么喝的--?
- 不, 不用了. 我有汤力朗姆酒了.
- Can l get you something--?
- No, no. l have a rum and tonic.
看见了.
l see.
我有个姐姐
以前常把朗姆酒加到茶里,
One of the sisters
used to put rum in her tea,
我当时听来像是天方夜谭, 所以...
and l thought it sounded exotic, so...
这一切对你来说都是新的, 对吧?
This is all new to you, isn't it?
我觉得惊奇不断, 好眩.
l feel constantly amazed, stunned.
音乐和人,
Music and people,
他们讲话和笑的方式,
the way they talk and laugh,
而他们中有些人
很明显是爱人.
and the way some of them
are so clearly in love.
对我来说就像是外语一样.
lt's like a foreign language to me.
我意识到言语不足以表达
我懂的有多么少啊.
l know just enough of the words
to realize how little l understand.
嗳, 我喜欢透过你眼睛
去看世界.
Man, l would love to see the world
through your eyes.
为什么?
Why?
噢, 如果我有机会
我可能会去做些不同的事.
Oh, there's some things
l might do different if l had the chance.
我也是.
Me too.
你瞧, 世事就是如此,
我以前失败过，而...
You see, the thing is,
l failed before and...
我很怕它会再次发生.
l'm just afraid it might happen again.
你想说说它吗?
You wanna talk about it?
现在不想说.
Not yet.
或许我能帮助你.
Maybe l can help.
你能吗?
Can you?
如果你想的话.
lf you want me to.
我可是很倔强的. 又极其任性.
l'm stubborn. Extremely willful.
我能应付得来.
l can handle that.
有些人觉得我是个怪人.
Some people think l'm strange.
我知道那是什么感觉.
l know the feeling.
我不能向你保证
我总是理性的
l couldn't promise you
that l would always make sense
或者去做些
你期待我去做的事.
or do things
that you would expect me to do.
安妮, 我不予任何冀望.
Annie, l don't expect anything.
那好吧，我接受你仁慈
和慷慨厚意.
Then l accept your kind
and generous offer.
好. 我很高兴.
Good. l'm glad.
我的, 我的, 我的.
My, my, my.
看我们在这...
What have we...
...找到了什么?
...here?
有可能是它吗?
Could it be?
是的.
Yes.
倒转的符号.
The symbol inverted.
现在...
Now...